是我。
C'est moi.
我还以为你不会出现了。
I thought you'd never show up.
我们正赶时间。
We're crowding call time.
钢琴弹起来。这会很短。我会把它编成密码。
Get the piano going. This will be a short one. I'll put it in code.
什么耸人听闻的吗?
Anything sensational?
不。有些沥青铀矿。四十车。
No. Some are pitchblende. Forty carloads.
——向北?-是的。为德国。
- Heading north? - Yeah. For Germany.
高杯酒。他甚至都没来得及签字。
Highball. He didn't even get the chance to sign off.
从捷克斯洛伐克沥青铀矿。从西班牙沥青铀矿。
Pitchblende from czechoslovakia. Pitchblende from Spain.
在过去的30天里从德国运出了250辆车。
Two hundred and fifty carloads out of Germany in the past 30 days.
英国情报机构表示，他们已经从挪威拿走了全部的独居石。
And British intelligence says they've taken the whole output of monazite from Norway.
我们的问题是我们没有足够的人来分析科学数据。
Our trouble is we haven't enough people who can analyse scientific data.
沥青铀矿和独居石。
Pitchblende and monazite.
我明天才回来。我得找个能分析的人谈谈。
I'll be out of town till tomorrow. I've got to talk to somebody who can analyse it.
谁在那?
Who's there?
一个兄弟会的老兄弟。
An old fraternity brother.
克莱门! 你好吗?
Why, clem! How are you?
不知道我现在怎么样。我在地窖里转来转去破门而入就为了找到你。
Don't know how I am. I've been wandering through cellars... And breaking down doors trying to get to you.
-你有事瞒着我吗?——没有。
- Are you hiding something from me? - No.
但你在瞒我什么?我以为你参军了。
But what are you hiding from me? I thought you were in the army.
为了让你明白，我是个上校。
To put you in your place, I'm a colonel.
-那为什么穿便服?-我在0.8.8。
- Then why the civilian clothes? - I'm in 0.8.8.
-没听说过。——这很好。我们不应该引起公众的注意。
- Never heard of it. - That's fine. We're not supposed to get publicity.
是战略服务办公室。
It's the office of strategic services.
在华盛顿，我们被称为秘密特工。
Around Washington we're called the cloak-and-dagger boys.
——听起来浪漫。——确定。非常。
- Sounds romantic. - Sure. Very.
我们有很多事要做，阿尔瓦。情报工作。士气的东西。
We do a lot of things, alvah. Intelligence work. Morale stuff.
敌后作战。
Operations behind the enemy lines.
既然这么保密，你为什么要告诉我这些?
Why are you telling me all this if it's so hush-hush?
最近的核物理研究进展如何?
How's work in nuclear physics these days?
——一般。-别靠近我。
- So-so. - Don't close up on me.
这也是秘密，克莱姆，政府的工作。
Well, it's hush-hush too, clem- government work.
我知道。你在做曼哈顿项目。
I know. You're working on the Manhattan project.
我就是为此而来的。
That's why I'm here.
这对你意味着什么?
What does this mean to you?
沥青铀矿铀。独居石的钍。
Pitchblende's for uranium. Monazite's for thorium.
我们不再使用钍了。235有更方便的原子结构。
We're not working with thorium anymore. 235 has a more convenient atomic structure.
德国人有没有可能知道一些我们不知道的关于钍的事?
Any chance the Germans have learned something about thorium we don't know?
德国人吗?
The Germans?
我可不这么认为。但这样的数量不是实验室能做的。
I wouldn't think so. But... quantities like these aren't for the laboratory.
它们是用于大规模行动的。
They're for large-scale operations.
你觉得他们可能也在研究原子弹吗?
Do you think they might be working on an atomic bomb too?
我们都想知道。他们有头脑。
We've all wondered. They got the brains.
他们对核裂变的了解和我们一样多。
They know as much about nuclear fission as we do.
阿尔瓦，他们在研究原子弹。
Well, alvah, they are working on an atom bomb.
嗯哼。克莱姆，这是我第一次后悔自己是科学家。
Mm-hmm. Clem, this is the first time I was ever sorry I'm a scientist.
为什么?
Why?
听着，再过几年，我们就能分解这个苹果的原子结构。
Look, in a few years, we'll be able to break up the atomic structure of this apple.
当我们这样做的时候，它将成为一个炸弹。
When we do that, it will become a bomb.
这个小苹果的能量可以摧毁这所大学，整个城市，它的医院，图书馆，它的优秀的医学院，更不用说里面所有的人了。
The energy in this one, little apple could pulverise this university, this whole town, its fine hospitals, its libraries, its wonderful medical schools, to say nothing of all the people in it.
但是…我们还是做不出一个，小苹果。
But... We still wouldn't be able to make one, little apple.
我们有点超前了。社会还没有为原子能做好准备。
We're running ahead of ourselves. Society isn't ready for atomic energy.
我吓坏了。
I'm scared stiff.
这是第一次，成千上万的科学家联合在一起，共同研究什么?
For the first time, thousands of allied scientists are working together to make what?
一个炸弹!但是，战前谁愿意资助消灭肺结核的科学研究呢?
A bomb! But who was willing to finance science before the war to wipe out tuberculosis?
我们什么时候能拿到十亿美元去消灭癌症?
And when are we gonna be given a billion dollars to wipe out cancer?
我告诉你，我们可以在一年内完成。
I tell you, we could do it in one year.
但如果有人要研制原子弹，你希望是我们，而不是纳粹。
But if anybody's going to develop the atom bomb, you want it to be us, not the Nazis.
没有多少选择。
Not much choice in that.
阿尔瓦，我们需要更多训练有素的人。
Alvah, we need more trained men on this.
我们得知道德国人走了多远。
We've got to know how far the Germans have gone.
他们工作的地方。我们如何阻止他们。
Where they're working. How we can stop them.
我们大部分的探员都没有装备。
Most of our agents aren't equipped.
他们不知道要找什么。
They don't know what to look for.
他们遗漏了一些线索，我知道。这是一场比赛。
They're missing clues, I know. This is a race.
不是德国人就是我们。
It's the Germans or us.
我们得让更多的科学家加入我们的队伍。
We've got to get more scientists into our outfit.
那我在这里做什么呢?
How about what I'm doing here?
我已经被授权让你离开了。你知道问题所在。
I'm already authorised to take you off. You know the problem.
你是单身。你会说一点德语。但你必须成为志愿者。
You're single. You can speak a little German. But you've got to volunteer.
曾经有一段时间，我想成为某种秘密特工。
There was a time when I thought I'd like to become some sort of a secret agent.
我八岁的时候就放弃了。
I gave it up at the age of eight.
好吧，兄弟，你现在是间谍了。
Okay, brother, you're now a spy.
我有两张回华盛顿的机票。
I've got two plane tickets back to Washington.
我能有时间结束这一切吗?
Can I even have time to wind things up here?
通常我们会给你几周的时间，但我想让你看看这个。
Ordinarily we'd give you a few weeks, but I want you to take a look at this.
认识她吗?
Know her?
卡特琳·洛多医生，最伟大的医生之一。
Dr. Katerin lodor, one of the great ones.
在匈牙利被卖给纳粹之前我是我的科学模特。
Used to be my scientific pinup girl before Hungary sold out to the Nazis.
我猜她现在正处于德国原子研究的中心。
I suppose now she's right in the centre of German atomic work.
-她在瑞士。从什么时候开始?
- She's in Switzerland. - Since when?
大约六个星期。她一个人翻越了阿尔卑斯山。
About six weeks. She came over the alps... alone.
她因肺炎住进了苏黎世的一家医院。
She's been in a hospital in Zurich with pneumonia.
几天前她和美国领事馆取得了联系。
A few days ago she got in touch with the American consulate.
她说要见我们的一位科学家。
Said she wanted to see one of our scientists.
你不知道这让我有多开心。
You don't know how happy that makes me feel.
如果她刚离开德国，她会知道这是一个极好的机会!
If she's just out of Germany she can tell... this is a terrific break!
如果你不再为此感到高兴，回家收拾行李，过几天你就能见到她了。——好的。
If you'd stop feeling so happy about it and go home and pack a bag, - you can see her in a couple of days. - Okay.
我希望您对您的房间满意。
I hope you find your room satisfactory.
谢谢schoen表示。
Danke schoen.
-非常抱歉，先生-很好
- Very sorry, sir. - Quite all right.
-给你。,非常感谢。
- Here you go. - Danke sehr.
不要回头。
Don't turn around.
你要见的女士在安吉洛医院。
The lady you want to see is at the Angelo hospital.
房间1-6-8。她的名字叫希柯蒂太太。
Room 1-6-8. She's there under the name of Mrs. Hickerty.
你可以进来了。
You may come in.
请不要太久，威尔逊先生。
Not too long, please, Mr. Wilson.
你的真名是什么，威尔逊先生?
What is your real name, Mr. Wilson?
——阿尔瓦Jesper。-我知道你的工作。
- Alvah Jesper. - I know your work.
感谢上帝你来了。你不知道我有多感激你。
Thank god you've come. You don't know how indebted I am to you.
对我?
To me?
当人们发现你所做的一切，他们会知道你不仅是一位伟大的物理学家，还是一位伟大的女性。
When people find out what you've done, they'll know you're not only a great physicist, but a great woman.
也许吧。故事还没有结束。
Maybe. The story isn't ended yet.
人们会怎么想?你会怎么想……-如果我回德国?——回去?
What will people think? What will you think... - If I were to go back to Germany? - Go back?
但这不是你翻越阿尔卑斯山或者联系我们的原因。
Oh, but that isn't why you crossed the alps or got in touch with us.
不。但你看，我以为我在这里很安全。
No. But you see, I thought I'd be safe here.
我不是。德国人找到我了。
I'm not. The Germans have found me here.
昨天我收到一封盖着苏黎世邮戳的信。
Yesterday I got a letter postmarked Zurich.
我要去意大利工作。
I'm to go to Italy to work.
我一直在那里和波尔达合作。
I've been collaborating there with polda.
——Giovanni polda ?——是的。
- Giovanni polda? - Yes.
如果我不回去，从周日开始，每天都有十个匈牙利反纳粹分子被带出集中营并被枪毙。
If I don't return, beginning Sunday, ten anti-Nazi Hungarians are to be taken out of concentration camps... And shot each day.
每天，他们都会给我一封写有名字的信。
Each day, they promise me a letter with names.
带着死者的照片。
With photographs of the dead people.
所以德国人在研究原子武器?
So the Germans are working on atomic weapons?
意大利人。他们正在协调。
Italians too. They are coordinated.
如果你回去，你的工作帮助他们成功，会发生什么?
Then what would happen if you went back and your work helped them to succeed?
如果我留在这里会怎么样?
What happens if I stay here?
我不能眼睁睁地看着无辜的人因为我而被枪杀。
I can't live knowing that innocent people are being shot because of me.
我将回去。
I'll go back.
我将毒药。我无法做出其他决定。
I'll take poison. I can't decide any other way.
不如你回去和波尔达医生一起工作吧?
Suppose you went back to work with Dr. Polda?
但是你在工作中遇到过困难吗?障碍。
But you met difficulties in your work? Obstacles.
——明白了吗?——是的。
- Understand? - Yes.
这是可能的。这是可能的。
That's possible. That's possible.
如果你觉得自己足够强大，你也可以帮助我们，提供一些信息。
And if you felt strong enough for it, you could help us, too, with information.
-有沟通的方式吗?-我想是的。
- There are ways of communicating? - I think so.
我得和你讨论一下。必须做出安排，相信我，我有足够的力量去做这件事。
I'll have to discuss it. Arrangements will have to be made, and- believe me, I would be strong enough for that.
但你得快点。他们只给了我周日的期限。
But you have to hurry. They've given me only until Sunday.
在我回去之前，我们得谈谈。
Before I go back, we have to talk.
我需要你提供的所有信息。
I'll need every bit of information you have.
如果你知道当英国人轰炸挪威的重水工厂时，他们是如何击退他们的，这对他们来说意味着几个月的延迟。
If you only knew how the British set them back... When they bombed that heavy water plant in Norway it meant a delay of months for them.
但如果你不能安排呢?
But what if you can't arrange this?
-可以安排。——我将
- It can be arranged. - I will
噢,我忘了。他们一直在担心我的肺。我该照x光了。
Oh, I forgot. They keep worrying over my lungs. I'm due for an X-ray.
-我很乐意等。-明天早上再来。
- I'll be glad to wait. - Come back tomorrow morning.
那我就更有力气了。我们可以聊一整天。
I'll have more strength then. We can talk all day.
什么都不用担心。
Don't worry about anything.
今晚我将睡觉。
Tonight I'll sleep.
知道你能入睡的感觉真好。
Such a good feeling to know you can sleep.
-有我的电话吗?——不,先生。
- Are there any calls for me? - No, sir.
我在等一个电话。请在吧台那边叫我好吗?
I'm expecting a call. Will you please have me paged at the bar?
很高兴,先生。
Glad to, sir.
哦,对不起。莱西，你怎么了?
Oh, excuse me. Lassie, what's the matter with you?
非常抱歉。她总是被人踩在脚下。
I'm terribly sorry. She's always getting caught under people's feet.
那是狗的特权。
That's a dog's privilege.
——马提尼。——是的,先生。
- Martini. - Yes, sir.
请非常干燥。
Very dry, please.
是的。这一定是个美国人。
Yah. This must be an American.
看你穿的衣服，点的酒，肯定是美国人。
By your clothes, the drink you ordered, surely an American.
而且你是新来的。
And by the fact that you are new in this hotel.
也许你就这么结束了?
Perhaps you are just over, huh?
祝健康!
Prosit!
告诉我，哦，哦。原谅我!
Tell me, oh, oh. Pardon me!
没关系。
It's all right.
告诉我,朋友。我们会赢吗?
Tell me, friend. Are we going to win?
我是说我们的事业。当然,我反纳粹。
Our cause, I mean. Naturally, I'm anti-Nazi.
最大的问题是美国的工业。
The big question is American industry.
例如，如果钢铁产量能达到9500万吨，那么我们就赢了。
If steel production, for instance, can go to 95 million tons, then we will win.
现在告诉我，在美国过得怎么样?
So now tell me, how are things in america, huh?
原谅我。
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
你非常介意我坐下吗?
Would you mind terribly if I sat down?
哦,我明白了。
Oh, I see.
我们的盖世太保朋友一直在压榨你。他对新来的人都这样。
Our gestapo friend has been pumping you. He does that to everyone new around here.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
-我叫安德鲁·威尔逊。-我叫安·道森。
- My name is Andrew Wilson. - Mine's Ann Dawson.
-你说话像个美国人。——我。
- You talk like an American. - I am.
你知道，那边的弗里茨，他不是很危险，但他是个可怕的讨厌鬼。
You know, Fritz over there, he's not very dangerous, but he's a frightful bore.
-你最好离他远点。——威尔逊先生吗?
- You better stay away from him. - Mr. Wilson?
威尔逊先生，有你的电话。
Call for you, Mr. Wilson.
——谢谢。我可以吗?——当然。
- Thank you. May I? - Certainly.
——威尔逊说。——仔细听。
- Wilson speaking. - Listen carefully.
没必要的话，别在电话里说任何话。
Don't say anything over this phone you don't have to.
——是吗?-一定是哪里出问题了。
- Yes? - Something must have got snafued.
你遇到了双杀。为什么- - - - - -
You've run into a double play. Why did-
和你坐在一起的那位小姐是那边最狡猾的操作员之一。
that tootsie you're sitting with is one of the slickest operators on the other side.
把酒倒下去，但不要太快，让酒慢慢淡下去。在本垒等我。
Knock down that grog, but not too fast, and fade. Wait for me at home plate.
——麻烦?-没什么我处理不了的。
- Trouble? - Nothing I can't handle.
我们陷入困境了。他们发现了你的事。
We're in a jam. They found out about you.
你向他们通风报信了。你犯了个错误。
Somewhere along the line you tipped them off. You made a mistake.
-我完全按照指示做了。-那他们是怎么绑架洛多医生的?
- I followed instructions to the letter. - Then how did they kidnap Dr. Lodor?
你在说什么?我今天早上见过她。
What are you talking about? I saw her this morning.
从你见到她到现在，她消失了。
Between the time you saw her and now, she disappeared.
她没有走出去。她被绑架。
She didn't walk out. She was kidnapped.
当我看到那个叫道森的女人和你在一起时，我就知道有什么不对劲。
I knew there was something up when I saw that Dawson woman with you.
你去机场后都在干什么?把每个动作都告诉我。
What have you been doing since the time you hit the airport? Give me every move.
-我通过了海关。-你说什么?
- I came through the customs. - What did you say?
-告诉他们我在值班。——什么?
- Told them I was in watches. - Nothing else?
——继续。
- Go on.
门口有个摄影师。
At the barrier, there was a photographer.
他看起来不像那篇文章，所以我没让他给我拍照。
He didn't look like the real article, so I didn't let him snap my photo.
那就是你的错误。
Thafsit that's your mistake.
我们一直在远离洛多。
We've been keeping away from lodor.
你没让他给你拍照，他们知道你是有原因的。所以他们跟踪了你。
You didn't let him take your picture, they knew you had a reason. So they trailed you.
所以他们才知道你见过洛多。所以他们抓走了她。
That's how they knew you saw lodor. That's why they snatched her.
所以他们才让道森盯着你。
That's why they put Dawson on you.
我以为我很聪明。
I thought I was being smart.
算了吧。你是怎么知道的?你是这一行的新手。
Forget it. How were you to know? You're new at this business.
所以他们绑架了她。
So they kidnapped her.
我们可以做点什么。
There's something we can do about it.
找到道森的房间号码。我得到的想法。
Get the number of Dawson's room. I'm getting ideas.
与此同时，让你进一步了解这个叫道森的女人。
Meanwhile, let your acquaintance with this Dawson woman develop.
你好。请告诉我道森太太的房间号码好吗?
Hello. Will you tell me the number of Mrs. Dawson's room, please?
呃,谢谢你。不，你不必打电话给她。
Uh, thank you. No, you needn't call her.
- 221。- 221。
- 221. - 221.
-你有火柴吗?-好的，先生，给你。
- You got a match? - Yes, sir. Here you are.
哦，不用麻烦了，先生，我去给您取。谢谢你！
Oh, don't bother, sir. I'll pick them up for you. Thank you.
你好，你真准时。进来。
Hello, you're certainly prompt. Come in.
你不坐下吗?晚饭前喝一杯吗?
Won't you sit down? Have a drink before dinner?
——谢谢。-我去拿我的围巾。
- Thank you. - I'll just get my wrap.
别管包装了。我们今晚不吃饭了。
Never mind the wrap. We'll skip dinner this evening.
——真的吗?-我有些东西要读给你听。
- Really? - I have something to read to you.
哦。你在给我写诗吗?
Oh. Are you writing me poetry?
在某种程度上，是的。这是一首十四行诗的副本，几分钟后就会送到德国领事馆。
In a way, yes. This is a copy of a sonnet... Which will be dropped off at the German consulate within a few minutes.
是写在银行信纸上的。
It's written on bank stationery.
上面写着:“亲爱的先生们，我只是这家银行的一名职员，”但我是德国真正的朋友。
It reads, "dear sirs, I am only a clerk in this bank, "but I'm a true friend of Germany.
“您应该知道，有个叫安·道森的人，大概对我们很友好，最近在我们这儿存了五千美元。”
"You ought to know that a certain Ann Dawson, presumably friendly to us, has recently deposited with us the sum of 5,000 American dollars."
哦,那太荒唐了。
Oh, that's ridiculous.
陪同她去银行的是一个高大的美国人，"我以前从未见过他。
"She was accompanied to the bank by a tall American, "whom I have never seen before.
“是他付的钱。”
"It was he who paid over the money."
-署名:“一个警惕的朋友。”-但是我-呃。postscript。
- Signed, "a watchful friend." - But i- uh-uh. There's a postscript.
“道森太太和那个高个子美国人似乎很相亲相爱。”
"Mrs. Dawson and that tall American seemed very fond of each other."
但我不明白，这一切意味着什么，德国领事馆为什么要对我感兴趣?
But I don't understand, what does all this mean, and why should the German consulate be interested in me?
我在瑞士是因为我丈夫。
I'm in Switzerland because of my husband.
他在空军服役。他被击落了，现在在这里实习。
He's in the air force. He was shot down, and he's interned here.
-我是美国人。——从技术上说,是的。
- I'm an American. - Technically, yes.
你在美国出生，在那里长大。
You were born in america, you were raised there.
但在1935年，你以希尔达·温特斯的名义加入了德美同盟。
But in 1935, you joined the German-American bunde under the name of hilda winters.
1937年，你因组织反犹太和反黑人骚乱而被捕。
In 1937, you were arrested for organising anti-semitic and anti-negro riots.
1939年，你在柏林的哥伦比亚大厦，为盖世太保工作。
In 1939, you were in the Columbia house, Berlin, working for the gestapo.
从1940年开始，你就在瑞士工作。
Since 1940, you've been operating in Switzerland.
是的，你的确是一个美国人，但是承认这一点让我很不舒服。
Yes, you're an American all right, but it makes my stomach crawl to admit it.
你撒谎的猪!
You lying pig!
你以为盖世太保会相信这种拙劣的诬陷吗?
Do you think the gestapo will believe a clumsy frame-up like this?
我想他们会的。我们很快就会知道了。
I think they will. We'll find out soon enough.
现在7:28。我七点半会接到一个电话。
It's now 7:28. I'll be getting a phone call at 7:30.
如果到时你还没告诉我我想知道的事，信就会送到。
If you haven't told me what I want to know by then, the letter will be delivered.
他们会嘲笑你的。
Why, they'll laugh at it.
我想他们会做些检查的。
I rather think they'll do some checking.
一个长得像你的女人今天和我一起在银行。
A woman who looks like you was in the bank with me today.
她的签名和你的一模一样。
Her signature was an exact duplicate of yours.
看。
Look.
他们一定时常为你担心。
They must have been worried about you from time to time.
他们有个理论，一旦是德国人，就永远是德国人。
They have a theory, once a German, always a German.
这可能也适用于美国人。
It may apply to Americans too.
他们知道我不会背叛他们。他们知道我有多忠诚。
They know I wouldn't betray them. They know how loyal I've been.
直到一个美国探员对你下手。给你钱。
Until an American agent went to work on you. Offered you money.
与此同时，也重新点燃了我内心深处微弱的爱国主义火花。
And at the same time, rekindled that faint spark of patriotism deep down inside.
你知道吗，如果他们杀你的原因泄露出去，你可能会成为一个女英雄。
You know, if it ever gets out why they shot you, you may end up as a heroine.
我只想知道凯特琳·洛多在哪里?
All I want to know is where is katerin lodor?
如果你告诉我，那封信就会被销毁。
If you tell me, the letter will be destroyed.
安德鲁!请相信我，我不知道她在哪里。
Andrew! Please believe me, I don't know where she is.
发出去
Send it
——等等!——等等。
- wait! - Hang on.
她在雪绒花滑雪俱乐部。
She's at the edelweiss ski club.
沿着山路从穆阿特村出发。
Up the mountain road... From the village of mouat.
现在是关闭的。
It's closed now.
-怎么样?-一切都井然有序。
- How is it? - Everything in order.
图书馆里的一个守卫。楼上的另一个睡着了。
One guard in the library. The other upstairs asleep.
护士睡着了。Lodor的房间门。
Nurse asleep. Lodor's room door.
开始,埃里克。
Get started, Eric.
我们进去后，你要坚守岗位。
Take your post when we go in.
护士!得到她!
The nurse! Get her!
让我走!
Let me go!
嗯,就是这样。
Well, that's that.
世界上大概还有十个人有她这样的头脑。
In the whole world there were perhaps ten people with a mind equal to hers.
有一次，为了解决一个问题，她发明了一套全新的数学体系。
Once, to solve a problem, she invented a whole new system of mathematics.
她本可以完成的工作。
The work she still could have done.
-所以你来瑞士就白来了?——没有。
- So you came to Switzerland for nothing? - No.
你是说“不”吗?
Did you say, "no"?
她告诉我，她一直在和一个叫乔瓦尼·波尔达的意大利人合作。
She told me she had been working with an Italian, Giovanni polda.
德国的顶尖科学家都是有良好声望的纳粹党员。
The leading German scientists are all Nazi party members in good standing.
战前我和波尔达通信。
I corresponded with polda before the war.
-他当时很友好。-你怎么知道他现在很友好?
- He was friendly then. - How do you know he's friendly now?
我不喜欢。但下一步必须是意大利
I don't. But the next step has to be Italy
三十秒。
Thirty seconds.
-你的意大利朋友很准时。——好。我们走吧，艾。
- Your Italian friends are on time, it. - Good. Let's shove off, ai.
谢谢你,队长。
Thank you, captain.
祝你好运。
Good luck.
-把她拉进来。狐猴的一种,先生。
- Haul her in. - Aye-aye, sir.
上车吧,。
Hop in, al.
我猜你是从墨索里尼那里租的这辆车。
I suppose you rent this truck from Mussolini.
排序的。司机白天为他工作，晚上为我们工作。
Sort of. The driver works for him by day and for us at night.
-可以抽烟吗?——确定。
- All right to smoke? - Sure.
——谢谢。——谢谢。
- Thanks. - Grazie.
哦。吉娜见面。
Oh. Meet Gina.
吉娜，这位是柏林威廉大帝研究所的纳尔海姆博士。
Gina, meet herr Dr. Nalheim of the kaiser Wilhelm institute in Berlin.
-我们叫他ai。-你好，你好。
- We call him ai. - Hello, ai hello.
不,混乱关系。
No, tre.
Documenti, Documenti !
Documenti, documenti!
杀了香烟。
Kill the cigarettes.
您看!您看!
Presto! Presto!
-我不会说意大利语，一个都不会?
- I don't talk Italian - not even any?
我知道但丁的一节诗。
I know one verse from Dante.
你这次的任务是什么?
What kind of a mission do you make this time?
你穿得连德国医生都不合适。
You're not even dressed right for a German doctor.
哦,别担心。我会成为一个德国医生的。
Oh, don't worry. I'll be a German doctor all right.
波达知道他要来吗?
Does polda know he's coming?
我们要给他一个惊喜。
We're going to surprise him.
——这是疯了。-这是一个非常重要的任务。
- That's crazy. - This is a very important mission.
非常。我们所有人都有一个工作要做。
Very. All of us have one job to do.
那就是把ai安全带进去见波达医生，然后再把他带出来。
That's to take ai safely in to see Dr. Polda, and then take him out again.
好吧。
All right.
现在波尔达总是从实验室回家吃午饭。
Now polda always comes home from his laboratory for noon dinner.
之后，他睡了一个小时。然后他在他的书房工作。
After that, he sleeps for one hour. Then he works in his study.
他下午有客人吗?
Does he have visitors in the afternoon?
在我观察房子并得到报告的十天里，只有三个人来过。
Well, in the ten days I watched the house and get reports, only three visitors came.
-谁在房子里?——一个管家。老女人，善良，愚蠢。
- Who's in the house? - A housekeeper. Old woman, nice, stupid.
一个厨师。好厨师。法西斯。
A cook. Good cook. Fascist.
还有四个秘密警察。Ovra男人。两天。两个晚上。
And four secret police. Ovra men. Two for day. Two for night.
-其中的首领是路易吉。-检查完毕了吗?
- And the chief of them is Luigi. - Is it all checked?
有天晚上我把他灌醉了，他问过我。
Checked from the cook when I got him drunk one night.
从和我们在一起的波尔达牙医罗摩里医生那里查到的。
Checked from Dr. Romoli, dentist of polda who is with us.
每天都被马soli和他的行为所检查，被我的眼睛所检查。
Checked by marsoli and his ways and checked by my eyes every day.
现在你知道一流的信使能做什么了。
Now you know what a first-rate courier can do.
你很擅长这个，战后我会给你找份工作。
You're so good at this, I'll get you a job at it after the war.
-我不喜欢你那样说话。-我只是开个玩笑。
- I don't like you to talk like that. - I was only joking.
-我不喜欢你开玩笑。——我很抱歉。
- I don't like yourjoking. - I'm sorry.
-你对路易吉了解多少?-一个聪明人。训练有素。
- What do you know about Luigi? - A smart man. Well trained.
这是令人欣慰的。
That's comforting.
我怎么去房子呢?
How do I get to the house itself?
去房子的事已经安排好了。但要想进去……
To get to the house has been arranged. But to get inside...
威廉二世研究所的纳尔海姆博士来见波尔达教授。
Dr. Nalheim from kaiser Wilhelm institute to see professor polda.
——Passaporto。-说德语。
- Passaporto. - Sprechen sie deutsch.
护照请。
Passport please.
——Nalheim博士?
- Dr. Nalheim?
Kaiser Wilhelm研究所。
Kaiser Wilhelm institute.
谢谢,doktor先生。
Danke, herr doktor.
谢谢。
Danke.
我不是纳尔海姆医生。
I'm not doctor nalheim.
我是美国物理学家，我的名字是——我不在乎你叫什么!
I'm an American physicist and my name is- I don't care what your name is!
-你是美国人!-波达医生，听着。
- You're an American! - Dr. Polda, listen.
我不想听!
I don't want to listen!
你来这里真是疯了。你怎么敢把我置于如此危险的境地。
You're insane to come here. How dare you put me in such danger.
几年前，你给我写了一封信。
A few years ago, you wrote me a letter.
在结尾处你说，“只有服务于全人类的自由科学，才能成为优秀的科学。”
At the end of it you said, "only a free science in the service... Of all humanity can be a good science."
-你是谁?——阿尔瓦Jesper。
- Who are you? - Alvah Jesper.
它是什么?
What is it?
谢谢。
Grazie.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
好吧。我不能背叛我的科学家同事。
All right. I can't betray a fellow scientist.
但你一定是疯了才会来这里。我们没什么可谈的。
But you must be insane to come here. We have nothing to talk over.
什么都没有。
Nothing.
请走吧。
Please go.
-你在研究核裂变。——是明智的。走了。
- You're working on nuclear fission. - Be sensible. Go.
你在为纳粹工作。我知道。
You're working for the Nazis. I know that.
但我不敢相信你愿意这么做。
But I can't believe you're doing it willingly.
哦,心甘情愿,情愿。这有什么关系?
Oh, willingly, unwillingly. What does it matter?
你无权来这里危及我的生命。
You have no right to jeopardise me by coming here.
我有这个权利。卡特琳·洛多给了我权利。
I have the right. Katerin lodor gave me the right.
-你看见卡特琳了?-就在纳粹杀死她之前。
- You saw katerin? - Just before the Nazis killed her.
Katerin,死了。
Katerin, dead.
——Katerin,死了。——被谋杀的。
- Katerin, dead. - Murdered.
她死是因为她不让罪犯利用她的科学知识。
She died because she wouldn't let criminals use her science.
-但你让他们利用了你。-你想要什么?
- But you're letting them use you. - So what do you want?
他们会把我也杀了吗?
That they should murder me too?
——不。但我需要信息。-我要我的生活。
- No. But I want information. - And I want my life.
这是那个从皇家学院辞职而不愿与墨索里尼握手的乔瓦尼·波尔达吗?
Is this the Giovanni polda who resigned from the royal academy... Rather than shake hands with Mussolini?
好吧。我变成了一个懦夫。鄙视我。
All right. I've become a weakling. Despise me.
我不在乎别人。
I don't care about people.
我只关心我自己。只有我自己。
I care about myself. Only myself.
你就是在说谎。这可不是伟大的波尔达人在说话。
You're lying. That's not the great polda talking.
你在害怕什么?他们对你有什么把柄?
What are you afraid of? What hold do they have on you?
把柄?没有把柄。我像空气一样自由。
Hold? No hold. I'm free as air.
他们所拥有的是这个世界上我唯一关心的人，我的女儿玛丽亚。
All they have is the only person in the world I care about, my daughter Maria.
他们抓了她。他的主人和我的主人。
They have her. His masters and mine.
我把他的肖像保存在这里，这样别人就会认为我很爱国。这样我就有东西可恨了。
I keep his portrait here so others will think I'm patriotic... And so I can have something to hate.
自从创世以来，从来没有一个人像我这样憎恨别人。
Not since the beginning of time... Has there been a man who has a hatred like me.
-那就跟他们打。-他们抓了我女儿。
- Then fight them. - They have my daughter.
他们让她每周给我寄一张明信片。
They let her send me a postcard once a week.
我让他们向我讨教。
And I let them pick my brains.
每周，我都会哭一次。
Once a week, I cry.
其他的晚上我喝酒。
The other nights I drink.
现在他们威胁要带她去德国。
Now they threaten to take her into Germany.
我说了一些他们不喜欢的话。只是一件小事。
I said something they didn't like. Only a little thing.
我忘了我自己。
I forgot myself.
你不知道他们也可以带你去德国吗?
Don't you know they can take you into Germany too?
他们被推到这里。你觉得他们撤退后会离开你吗?
They're being pushed back here. You think they'll leave you if they retreat?
不。他们不会离开我的。除非我被榨干了。
No. They won't leave me. Not till I'm squeezed dry.
-但你还是会服侍他们?-他们抓了玛丽亚。
- But still you'll serve them? - They have Maria.
为了她，我愿意为任何人服务。
For her I'll serve anyone.
如果她在另一个国家是安全的呢?
Suppose she were safe in another country?
——什么?-可以的。她在哪里呢?
- What? - It can be done. Where is she?
她被允许在佩鲁贾的一家酒店被看守。
She's permitted to leave under guard in a hotel in perugia.
albergo精益求精。
The albergo excelsior.
让她留在英国吧。美国。给我一个她的笔迹。我们可以做得更好。我们也可以带你出去。
Let her be in england. America. Give me one letter in her handwriting... We can do better than that. We can take you out too.
你不是在和一个又老又病的人玩吧?
You are not playing with an old, sick man?
——没有。-这对她来说很危险，不是吗?
- No. - It will be dangerous for her, won't it?
它可以安排，安全。
It can be arranged, safely.
你可以相信我。
You can trust me.
信任你吗?
Trust you?
我在法西斯主义统治下生活太久了。我不相信任何人。
I've lived too long under fascism. I trust no one.
但我做了一笔生意。如果你帮我，我就帮你。
But a business bargain I make. If you help me, I'll help you.
在那之前，别以为我是个傻瓜。我什么都不会告诉你。
Until then, don't think I'm a fool. I'll tell you nothing.
如果你是这种情况，波尔达医生。
If those are your conditions, Dr. Polda.
是的。
Yes.
照我说的做，也许我又会变成老波尔达了。
Do it, and maybe I'll become the old polda again.
"为人类服务的自由科学"
"A free science in the service of humanity."
“可以是唯一好的科学。”
"Can be the only good science."
现在来。我最好带你经过我的看门狗。
Come now. I'd better take you past my watchdogs.
-再见，教授先生。-再见，纳尔海姆博士。
- Auf wiedersehen, herr professor. - Auf wiedersehen, Dr. Nalheim.
再会。
Auf wiedersehen.
要找到波达的女儿可不是件容易的事。
Getting polda's daughter won't be any cinch.
我们该怎么做呢?
How do we go about it?
-我和他会处理的。你待着别动。-我也许能你也许能让我们陷入困境。这是所有。
- He and I will go about it. You stay put. - I might be able You might be able to land us in the soup. That's all.
你能在意大利闲逛多久不碰上盖世太保?
How long can you wander around Italy without running into the gestapo?
或者是ovra ?
Or the ovra?
你以为他们不会跟柏林核实你的文件吗?
You think they won't check your papers with Berlin?
不，先生，你待着别动，否则交易取消。
No, sir. You stay put or the deal is off.
好吧。我可以住在哪里?
Okay. Where can I stay?
-你有食品券吗?——是的。
- Do you have any food stamps? - Yes.
那这就是最好的地方。
Then this is the best place.
别让人看见，等着。
Just keep out of sight, and wait.
……如果我们抓到波尔达的女儿，我就在报纸上发布雷纳尔多·阿马迪中尉的死讯。
If... If we get polda's daughter, I'll put a notice in the papers announcing the death in action... Of lieutenant- lieutenant rinaldo amadi.
——Amadi ?——嗯。A-m-a-d-i。Amadi。
- Amadi? - Mm-hmm. A-m-a-d-i. Amadi.
当你看到它的时候，去罗莫利，波尔达的牙医。
When you see it, go to romoli's, polda's dentist.
他会让教授去找你的。
He'll have the professor there for you.
在北部有游击队的飞机场。我们将乘飞机去。
There are partisan airfields in the north. We'll go out by plane.
-你知道葡萄园吗，皮纳罗?——是的。
- You know the vineyard, pinaro's? - Yes.
采取polda那里。
Take polda there.
-你可能要多久?-需要多久就多久。
- How long are you likely to be? - As long as it takes.
-大概一周吧。-如果你找不到玛丽亚怎么办?
- A week maybe. - What if you don't get Maria?
如果我们完全没收到你的消息怎么办?
What if we don't hear from you at all?
战争的命运，艾。那你就只能靠自己了。
The fortunes of war, ai. You'll be on your own then.
这是你的外套。
Here's your coat.
谢谢你！谢谢。
Thank you. Grazie.
-就像新的一样。——Marsoli。Andiamo。
- It's just like new. - Marsoli. Andiamo.
——祝你好运。-吉娜，你能到外面看看吗?
- Good luck. - Gina, will you look outside please?
没关系。
It's all right.
吉娜,再见。
Gina, arrivederci.
——再见。-我会再见你的。
- Arrivederci. - I'll be seeing you.
好吧，别客气。
Well, make yourself at home.
谢谢。
Thanks.
我想让我在你手上比你想的要多。
I guess having me here on your hands was more than you bargained for.
在工作中，我们取其所来。
In our work we take what comes.
请不要再打量我了。
Please stop looking me over.
你长得很好看。
You're nice to look at.
我们就像歌剧中的一幕。
Just like a scene in the opera, we are.
百姓去。留下这对年轻夫妇独自一人。
The people go. The young couple is left alone.
快，这个年轻人一定要说些恭维话。这是预期。
Quick, the young man must make compliments. It's expected.
只是这里没有音乐，你也不是男高音。
Only there isn't any music, and you are not a tenor.
有你自己的方式，但在你了解我之前不要加我。
Have it your own way, but don't add me up before you know me.
我们要听一整晚吗?
Are we gonna have to listen to that all night?
也许你可以问问猫。
Maybe you ask the cat.
你满脑子都是醋，不是吗?
You're full of vinegar, aren't you?
这听起来饿了。
It sounds hungry.
如果人们饿了，只有猫才会饿。
Well, if people are hungry, it's only natural cats should be.
你有牛奶吗?
Have you got any milk for it?
牛奶吗?哦,我记得。
Milk? Oh, I remember.
它来自奶牛，不是吗?
It comes from cows, no?
好的婴儿。
Good for babies.
不过，我还是讨厌听到猫哭。也许来块面包。
Still, I hate to hear a cat cry. Maybe a piece of bread.
美国人喜欢猫，嗯?
The American likes cats, hmm?
只是你现在在欧洲。在这里，你可以在肉店里找到猫。
Only you're in Europe now. Here you find cats in butcher shops.
这是幸运的。但也许明天，就会掉进别人的炖锅里。
This one's been lucky. But by tomorrow maybe, plop into somebody's stew pot.
生活在一个不仅喂猫，而且还喂孩子的国家一定很好。
It must be nice to live in a country where not only cats are fed, but children.
拜托，我要去穿睡衣了。
Please, I'm going to put on my nightgown.
像你这样的女孩是怎么习惯这种生活的?
How does a girl like you get used to this kind of life?
你觉得会有人习惯吗?
Do you think anyone gets used to it?
我觉得你做得很好，吉娜。
I think you do wonderfully, Gina.
我从没见过这么有勇气的女孩。
I never knew a girl with so much courage.
勇气?
Courage?
你是个成年人，知道的那么少。
You're a grown-up man and know so little.
你不懂猫，也不懂人。-你怎么了，吉娜?
You know nothing about cats, - and nothing about people. - What's the matter with you, Gina?
哦，没关系，只不过你是从月球来的。
Oh, no matter, except you come from the moon.
而我们却像拉撒路一样生活。
And here we live like, like Lazarus.
我们躺在坟墓里等待救世主的到来。
We lie in the grave waiting for the saviour to come.
不过我不是从月球来的，像你这样的意大利人也不是随便躺着的。
Only I don't come from the moon, and Italians like you aren't just lying down.
你坐沙发太长了。你睡那张床。
You're too long for the couch. You take the bed.
——唔唔。在这项工作中，我们是同志。
- Mm-mmm. - In this work we're comrades.
——没有。-明天你的背就要断了。我希望。
- No. - Tomorrow you'll have a broken back. I hope.
谢谢。
Thanks.
嘿。
Hey.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
我再也听不到那只猫的声音了。
I don't hear that cat anymore.
在这个国家，连猫都知道哭是没有用的。
In this country even the cats learn it's no use to cry.
米迦，米迦，米迦，米迦，米迦。
Micha, micha, micha, micha, micha.
我希望她身上有跳蚤。
Here, I hope she has fleas.
对不起，我没有洋葱肝。
Excuse me, I have no liver with onions.
只有剩菜。
Only leftovers.
现在闭嘴，让我睡觉，否则我就把你扔出窗外。
Now you shut up and let me sleep, or I'll throw you right out the window.
晚安，各位。
Good night.
人工智能?
Ai?
是吗?
Yes?
我说的不全是真的。
I don't mean all I say.
我知道你不知道。
I know you don't.
晚安，各位。
Good night.
不!
No!
吉娜。
Gina.
吉娜!
Gina!
不要担心。一切都是好的。
Don't be worried. Everything's all right.
哎，你为什么要叫醒我?
Ai, why do you wake me?
-为什么要这样吓唬我?-你在做梦。
- Why frighten me like this? - You were dreaming.
你在睡梦中哭泣。
You were crying in your sleep.
哦,是的。
Oh, yes.
我记得。
I remember.
哦。
Oh.
告诉我可能会有帮助。
It might help to tell me about it.
你在散兵坑里战斗很久了，不是吗，吉娜?
You've been fighting in the foxholes a long time, haven't you, Gina?
今晚，我对自己说，现在，也许，也许，一整个星期，一切都会变得容易。
Tonight I, I say to myself, now maybe, maybe for, for a whole week, it'll be easy.
待在房间里。
Stay in the room.
唱歌一点。
Sing a little.
灰尘洗碗。
Dust wash dishes.
不。不容易的。
No. Not easy.
即使是在睡觉的时候。
Not even in sleep.
夫人多米尼克?
Signora Dominica?
它是什么?
What is it?
Si。
Si.
他的猫。他想要他的猫。
His cat. He wants his cat.
在那里。快。
Over there. Quick.
谢谢,小姐,谢谢。
Grazie, signorina, grazie.
不，不是意大利人。
No, non parlo italiano.
哦,congratulazioni,夫人。Congratulazioni。
Oh, congratulazioni, signori. Congratulazioni.
哦,是的。
Oh, si.
Buona命运,夫人。Buona命运,夫人
Buona fortuna, signore. Buona fortuna, signore
布拉瓦。Bravissima。
brava. Bravissima.
那只猫。肯定是猫。
The cat. It had to be the cat.
总是一些小事，一些我们无法计划的事情让我们最终落入警察手中。
It's always the little things, the things we can't plan that make us end up in the hands of the police.
-我们不能再呆在这里了。——为什么?
- We can't stay here any longer. - Why?
-他是特工吗?——没有。
- Is he an agent? - No.
但每个看门人都得报告家里有新来者。
But every janitor has to report any new person in the house.
我告诉他你是我丈夫。
I told him you're my husband.
你为什么这么做?
Why did you do that?
我不能去警局登记。
I can't register with the police.
-我们不能冒这个险——我知道。我犯了个错误。
- We can't risk that. - I know. I made a mistake.
-你知道其他安全屋吗?-我在思考。
- Do you know any other safe house? - I'm trying to think.
我们不能没日没夜地在街上走。我们肯定会被接走的。
We can't walk the streets day and night. We'd be picked up sure.
我知道。闭嘴，让我想想。
I know. Shut up for a minute, and let me think.
我们在这里完成。
We're finished here.
-这不是你的错。-我没必要说你是我丈夫。
- It's not your fault. - I didn't have to say you're my husband.
在我们的工作中没有那种骄傲的空间。
In our work there's no room for that sort of pride.
没有自尊，你就不会是吉娜，不要为你的自尊感到羞愧。
Without pride you wouldn't be Gina don't be ashamed of your pride.
昨晚，而现在，你说的话让我在这里感觉轻松多了。
Last night, and now, you say things that make me feel easier in here.
也许你觉得自己很仁慈。
Maybe you feel charity.
或者，你喜欢人?
Or maybe, you like people?
我喜欢猫。
Mostly I like cats.
这张照片是什么时候拍的，吉娜?
When was this picture taken, Gina?
就在战争之前。
Just before the war.
一百年前。
A hundred years ago.
运气吗?
Any luck?
一套公寓。两间房和一间浴室，住三天。
An apartment. Two rooms and a bath for three days.
——洗澡?是谁给了我们这些?-我曾经认识的一位女教师。
- A bath? Who's giving us all that? - A schoolmistress I once knew.
法西斯党员。
A fascist party member.
我告诉她我有一个德国朋友，非常重要，她非常以我为荣。
I told her I had a German friend who was very important, and she was very proud of me.
累了,吉娜吗?
Tired, Gina?
- - - - - -不坏。饿了吗?——嗯。
- Not bad. Hungry? - Hmm.
不,谢谢。
No, thanks.
苹果含有大量的能量。
There's a lot of energy in an apple.
那是什么?
What's that?
我一直在忙着等你呢。
Oh, I was trying to keep busy waiting for you.
但它是什么呢?
But what is it?
这叫做画正弦波的线积分。
It's called plotting the line integral of a sine wave.
哦，这并不像听起来那么难。
Oh, it's not as difficult as it sounds.
我想象着我正骑着其中的一匹马，试着算出我总共能走多远，同时上上下下。
I was imagining I was riding one of those horses, trying to figure out how far I would go altogether, going around and up and down at the same time.
上上下下的马。
Horses going up and down.
和孩子,音乐。
And kids, music.
-你来过这里吗，吉娜?——嗯。
- Ever come here, Gina? - Mm-hmm.
在战争之前。
Before the war.
音乐一直在播放“giovinezza”，一首法西斯歌曲。
The music played "giovinezza" all the time, a fascist song.
它破坏了我的兴致。
It spoiled it for me.
-你带着个男孩来?-是的。
- You come here with a boy? - Yeah.
你喜欢的那个?
One you liked?
他和我一起拍的照片。他演奏大提琴。
He was in the picture with me. He played the cello.
他现在在哪里?
Where is he now?
在某处。如果没有他的大提琴。
Somewhere. Without his cello.
也许战争结束后，我可能会回来。
Maybe after the war, I might come back.
我会带你来这里。但音乐会有所不同。
And I'd bring you here. But the music would be different.
战后会有很大的不同。
After the war a lot will be different.
但你不会回来了。
But you won't come back.
我可能会。为什么不呢?
I might. Why not?
现在的时间。我们可以去。
It's time now. We can go.
——哇。-今晚我是战前吉娜。
- Whoa. - Tonight I am pre-war Gina.
我在学校教我的小孩。
I teach my little children in school.
星期三我演奏室内乐。
Wednesday I play chamber music.
我很无辜的。
I'm very innocent.
我很容易脸红。
And I'm easy to blush.
-换一套衣服就可以了吗?-我们走着瞧吧。
- A change of clothes does all that? - Well, we'll see.
我还是很漂亮，不是吗?
I'm still pretty, no?
嗯，有一点。
Hmm, a little bit.
即使你不这么认为，我遇到的所有男人，他们都说我很漂亮。
Well, even if you don't think so, all the ovra men I meet, they tell me I'm pretty.
我认识一个人他长得又高又高，他移动着他的身体，像一颗炮弹，再见吧，亲爱的，再见吧。
I know a man he is long and tall, he moves his body, like a cannonball, fare thee well, my honey, fare thee well.
——那是什么?-一首美国牛仔歌曲。
- What's that? - An American cowboy song.
别那么滑稽。你从新亚利桑那州飞来的一架飞机教我的。
Don't look so funny. One of your shot-down fliers from new Arizona taught it to me.
——新墨西哥州。——新亚利桑那州。
- New Mexico. - New Arizona.
好的,新的亚利桑那州。
Okay, new Arizona.
他教我的。
He taught it to me.
其余的我都不知道。
The rest I never learned.
只有第一行。
Only the first lines.
他非常的不错。
He was nice.
现在。
Now.
我看起来怎么样?
How do I look?
——战前。-你是说真的吗?
- Pre-war. - Do you mean it?
我当然知道。
Of course I do.
我不是奥夫拉人。
I'm no ovra man.
-你为什么这么说?-是你提出来的
- Why do you say that? - You brought it up.
哦。我猜你是嫉妒了。嗯?
Oh. You're jealous, I suppose. Hmm?
你觉得我就不能吃醋吗?
Do you think I couldn't be jealous?
你想让我跳舞吗?
Do you want me to dance?
也许我是嫉妒，吉娜
Maybe I am jealous, Gina
不，别跟我做爱。不要成为我喜欢的人。
No, don't make love to me. Don't be somebody I like.
如果你想吻我，我也想吻你，那我们就吻吧。
If you feel like kissing me, and I feel like kissing you, so we kiss.
但是不要太认真。
But don't be serious.
在我的工作中，我亲吻时没有感觉。
In my job, I kiss without feeling.
上周，一个留着傻胡子的男人。
Last week, an ovra man with a silly moustache.
下个星期，是一头盖世太保肥猪。
Next week, a fat, gestapo pig.
吉娜。
Gina.
吉娜,女孩。
Gina, girl.
你为什么一直抽自己，吉娜?
Why do you keep whipping yourself, Gina?
你觉得，你觉得在地下当个信使好吗?
Do you think, you think it's good, to be a courier in the underground?
你觉得这很刺激，很英勇。
You think it's exciting, heroic.
不。如果你和人渣斗争，你就会变成人渣。这是所有。
No. If you fight scum, you become scum. That's all.
不。我知道你是什么人。
No. I know what you are.
离照片上的小女孩不远。
Not so far from that little girl in the picture.
到门口去。
Go to the door.
-再见，夫人。,晚上好。
- Buona sera, signora. - Buona sera.
呃,联合国的纪念品。
Uh, UN momento.
谢谢。
Grazie.
-是谁?-两姐妹为战争中的孤儿募捐。
- Who was it? - Two sisters collecting charity, for children orphaned by the war.
-这有什么不对吗?——好吧,等待。
- Anything wrong with that? - Well, wait.
我们得离开这里。
We've got to get out of here.
-她们不是真正的姐妹。-你怎么知道?
- They're not real sisters. - How do you know?
他们停在街角的一辆汽车旁。
They're stopping at an automobile parked on the corner.
-我们被监视了。来吧。-让我看看。
- We're being watched. Come on. - Let me see.
-离那扇窗户远点。-等一下。
- Stay away from that window. - Wait a minute.
我跟着感觉走。我内心很害怕，我要对你负责。
I follow my feelings. I feel scared inside, and I'm responsible for you.
-相信我的感觉。-我们不要太紧张了。
- Trust my feelings. - Let's not get too jumpy about this.
如果他们是警察，我们早就被捕了。
If they're from the police, we'd be arrested already.
我知道有什么不对劲。我比你有更多的经验。
I know there's something wrong. I have more experience than you have.
-我们必须马上离开这里。-好吧，吉娜，随你便。
- We must get out of here and quick. - All right, Gina have it your way.
我们今晚在这里很安全。
Here we'll be safe for the night.
我认为这是安全的。然后明天天一亮，我们就搬走。
I think this is safe. Then tomorrow, as soon as it gets light, we'll move.
好吧。
All right.
作为一栋被监视的房子，我们很容易就逃了出来。
For a house that was being watched, we got out awfully easy.
我相信我的感觉。
I trust my feelings.
我颤抖。
I'm shaking.
我浑身发抖。
I'm shaking all over.
你会崩溃的，吉娜你每天都会崩溃一点。
Now you'll go to pieces, Gina every day you fall apart a little more.
太长了。太多了。
Too long. Too much.
太多的担心，太多的恐惧。
Too much worry and too much fright.
太多的死亡。
Too much death.
吉娜，你会没事的。
Gina, you're going to be all right.
别担心。
Don't worry.
我希望你喜欢我。
I want you to like me.
我想让你嫉妒我。
I want you to be jealous over me.
我想让你以为我是一个从没被吻过的穿白裙子的女孩。
I want you to think I'm a girl in a white dress... Who has never been kissed before.
广告上登了。
It's in. The advertisement.
——在哪里?——在这里。
- Where? - Here.
“莱amadi中尉。”
"Lieutenant rinaldo amadi."
他们把波尔达的女儿救出来了。
They've got polda's daughter out.
现在我们必须去罗摩里餐厅。
Now we must go to romoli's.
-噩梦结束了，宝贝。-另一个开始，把polda弄出来。
- Nightmare's over, baby. - Another one starts, to get polda out.
——我们将管理。你给我买剃须刀了吗?——是的。
- We'll manage. Did you get me a razor? - Yes.
剃刀，刀片，还有……一块肥皂。
Razor, and a blade, and... a piece of soap.
谢谢。
Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
哎，在我们的工作中，你遇到一个男人或一个女人，一天或一个星期，然后再见。
Ai, in our work you meet a man or a woman, for a day or a week, then good-bye.
但有一天，我的心离我很近。
But in one day heart's come close.
也许在和平时期我甚至都不看你，说"愚蠢的美国游客"
Maybe in peacetime I don't even look at you, say, "silly American tourist."
但现在我告诉你，我很喜欢这个长长的美国人，我想让你知道。
But now I tell you, I like very much this long American, and I want you to know.
为什么只有“喜欢”，吉娜?
Why only "like," Gina?
这样更好，更简单。
It's better. Easier.
为什么?
Why?
有时候它是更好的。
Sometimes it's better.
哎哟!你得刮胡子了，快点儿。
Ouch! You must shave, and hurry.
我们得去罗摩利餐厅
We've got to go to romoli's
把你的外套给我。
Give me your coat.
把这个。
Take this.
从门口进去。
Get into that doorway.
吉娜,polda !
Gina, get polda!
听着，这就像杀死一条疯狗。
Look, it's just like killing a mad dog.
除了狗，你可以感到抱歉。他生病不是他的错。
Except for the dog you can feel sorry. It's not his fault he is sick.
Jesper医生，Jesper医生，什么事?
Dr.jesper - Dr. Jesper - yes?
我想你最好开车。
I think you'd better drive.
哦，没什么严重的。
Oh, it's nothing serious.
我这个年纪有点太兴奋了。
Just a little too much excitement at my age.
我一见到玛丽亚就会好的。
I'll be again all right as soon as I've seen Maria.
好吧。拐弯处停车。
All right. Stop around the bend.
Jesper
这是我第一次听到你的名字。
That's the first time I heard your name.
Jesper，我喜欢。
Jesper I like it.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
小指中尉愿为您效劳。
Lieutenant pinkie at your service.
——小手指。-请进，伙计们。
- Pinkie. - Come on in, folks.
没关系。小指。
It's okay. It's pinkie.
——嗨,ai。——小手指。
- Hi, ai. - Pinkie.
-认识一下波尔达教授。-你好，波达教授?
- Meet professor polda. - How do you do, professor polda?
-你好。-你从哪弄来的?
- How do you do. - Where'd you get that stuff?
哦,这个吗?我的旅行服装。
Oh, this? My traveling costume.
挺合身的，不是吗?
Kind of a nice fit, isn't it?
哦,pinaro见面。
Oh, meet pinaro.
伟大的老家伙。如果他穿着制服，他会有满满一箱水果沙拉。
Great old guy. If he were in uniform he'd have a chest full of fruit salad.
——Pinaro。——Benvenuti。
- Pinaro. - Benvenuti.
让我们进去。
Let's go in.
-这位是彼得罗-祝你好运，彼得罗。
- And, uh, this is Pietro. - Buona sera, Pietro.
——marsoli在哪?-他马上就来。
- Where's marsoli? - He'll be along any minute.
和波达小姐。
And with signorina polda.
-她安全吗?——绝对安全。
- Is she safe? - Perfectly safe.
很高兴她能再见到你。
And very happy she's going to see you again.
-遇到麻烦了吗?-整个行动都很顺利。
- Run into any trouble? - Not a hitch in the whole operation.
像一阵风。我们通过酒店里的一个小女孩解决的。
Went like a breeze. We worked it through a little girl in the hotel.
漂亮的孩子。一开始有点害怕，但我打动了她善良的本性。
Nice kid. A little scared at first, but I appealed to her better nature.
我们的秘鲁朋友整理了一些文件，这样就可以坐火车旅行了。——谢谢。
Our perugian friends fixed up some papers - that made it okay to travel by train. - Thank you.
今天下午我们在最近的城镇下了车。
This afternoon we got off at the nearest town.
我想其他人会让天黑后这里更容易。
I figured the others would make it easier here after dark.
所以我走在前面，检查了一下我们预定的行程。
So I came on ahead and checked on our reservations for the trip out.
——哦,pinaro。-我们在哪里和飞机会合?
- Oh, pinaro. - Where do we meet the plane?
在离这里四英里的田地里。
In a field about four miles from here.
谢谢。吉娜知道。
Grazie. Gina knows where.
我可以开车去吗?——几乎。不会花很长时间的。
- Can I go all the way by car? - Almost. It won't take long.
从科西嘉岛。飞机将在凌晨4点降落。
It's from corsica. The plane will land at 4:00 am.
他们会派什么样的飞机?有多大?
What sort of plane will they send? How big?
他们知道我们有四个人。
They know there are four of us going out.
我知道我应该希望他们快点来，这样一切就都结束了，但我能想到的是，一个小时后我们就要告别了。
I know I should be wishing they'd come quickly and it'll all be over, but all I can think of is, in one hour we'll say good-bye.
吉娜，飞机上还有空位。
Gina, there's room on the plane.
这里的人太少了，即使是一个逃跑的人，也会被严重怀念。
There's so few of us here, even one who runs away is badly missed.
你知道的。你不?
You know that. Don't you?
是的，我知道。
Yes, I know that.
未婚女子polda。
Signorina polda.
Benvenufi。
Benvenufi.
-来吧，小指?祈祷,祝福。
- Come va, pinkie? - Bene, bene.
女士们，女士们，我是波尔达女士
Signori e signora, ia signorina polda
但那不是玛丽亚!
But that's, that's not Maria!
——什么?-那不是玛丽亚!
- What? - That is not Maria!
她在哪里呢?我女儿呢?
Where is she? Where is my daughter?
在佩鲁贾公墓。
In the perugia cemetery.
她六个月前去世了。
She died six months ago.
不。不,那是不可能的。
No. No, that's impossible.
她一直给我写信。
She's been writing me steadily.
这笔迹很难模仿。
The handwriting is so hard to imitate.
德国人!
Germans!
这是没有用的。你被德国人包围了。
It is no use. You're surrounded by Germans.
扔掉你们的枪，举起手走出去。
Throw away your guns and march out with your hands up.
投降。这是你唯一的机会。
Surrender. It's your only chance.
下来!
Get down!
看来他们要慢慢来了。
Looks like they're gonna take their time about it.
他们可以负担得起。
They can afford to.
天亮的时候，他们可能会有一整团德国佬在外面。
They'll probably have a whole kraut regiment out there by daylight.
有时候一个人带球，有时候另一个人。
Ai, sometimes one guy carries the ball, sometimes another.
从地下室出去有条路。
There's a way out of here through the cellar.
-抓住老人和吉娜，快走。-我做不到，小指。
- Grab the old man and Gina and beat it. - I can't do it, pinkie.
现在别对我手软。没有时间。
Don't go soft on me now. There isn't time.
一小时后就天亮了，那架飞机等不及了。
It'll be light in an hour, and that plane can't wait.
-为什么我们不一起试试呢?-你能成功的唯一办法，就是我们开枪让他们相信我们还在这里。
- Why don't we all try it together? - The only way you can make it, is if we do enough shooting to convince them we're all still here.
-快走吧!——不,小手指。
- Now get going! - No, pinkie.
我的命令是带你进入这个国家，然后把你弄出来。
My orders were to get you into this country and get you out.
在这种时候不要对我手软!
Don't go soft on me at a time like this!
吉娜，把他从活板门弄出去。这是命令，你也是
Gina, get him out through the trapdoor. That's an order. For you too, ai
快!快!
Quick! Quick!
光了!
Light out!
Jespeh
吉娜!
Gina!
我只能给他们五分钟。
I can only give them five minutes.
他们来了!
There they come!
-吉娜，姑娘，战后-谁知道会发生什么?
- Gina, girl, after the war - Who knows what'll be then?
我回来了。
I'm coming back.
事物是变化的。
Things change.
——人们改变。-我会回来找你的，吉娜
- People change. - I'm coming back for you, Gina.
谁知道呢?
Who knows?
你不想让我去吗?如果你不喜欢，就说出来。
Don't you want me to? If you don't, say so.
-现在就说。——“希望”?
- Say it now. - "Want"?
“想要”?
"Want"?
超过生活。
More than living.
回来了。
Come back.
回来找我吧。
Come back for me.
再见,亲爱的。
Good-bye, my darling.
我会回来的。
I'll be back.